<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Woman: Making Data Science Happen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Woman: Making Data Science Happen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Agile to Change the Data Science Conversation</title>
      <link>/2018/02/using-agile-to-change-the-data-science-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/using-agile-to-change-the-data-science-conversation/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I described some of the root causes I believe cause common problems for data science teams. So what do we do?
The problems facing data science are largely a function of the newness of data science groups to companies and other large organizations. Software development was once in a similar position. One way they addresses these problems was with the Agile approach. I believe we can borrow from this to address the challenges data science faces today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pain of Data Science in Organizations</title>
      <link>/2018/02/the-pain-of-data-science-in-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/the-pain-of-data-science-in-organizations/</guid>
      <description>It is the best of data science times, it is the worst of data science times&amp;hellip; Data science is high in the hype cycle and considered the sexiest job of the 21st century. Data scientists are in demand, and the tools to do our jobs are getting better by the month. It&amp;rsquo;s a great time to be in data science!
However&amp;hellip; managing a data science group often feels like an uphill battle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I manage the decision sciences team at TransLoc, a mission-driven transit technology company in Durham, NC. I have particular interests in:
 Building analytics teams that have an impact on the organization Using data science and technology to be a force for good Data and the irrationality of human decision making All things R Women in tech  I spend a lot of time thinking about how to make data science groups effective and have been drawing from Agile practices in this process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>